Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Subject Files
2.1.3.1.3.2
Marist College
  Box 1513
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.1.3.2
  - Subject files: Emir Feisal, circa 1918 - 1927; 1 (Box 1513)
    - Emir Feisal, 1
    - Emir Feisal, 2
    - Verso: Syria Damascus King Feisal, May 1927, 2-verso
    - Emir Feisal, 3
  - Subject files: Germany, 1919; 2 (Box 1513)
    - Sparticide armoured car helping spread reign of terror in Berlin, 1
    - Verso: Sparticide armoured car helping spread reign of terror in Berlin, 1-verso
    - Sparticides defending railway office in Freiburg, 2
    - Verso: Sparticides defending railway office in Freiburg, 2-verso
    - The Freiburg Soldatinsat Dr. Walter Riesenburger - its chairman, in center of first row, 3
    - Verso: The Freiburg Soldatinsat Dr. Walter Riesenburger - its chairman, in center of first row, 3-verso
    - American from Galveston who was in Germany when war broke out. He became a U-boat sailor and is now a Sparticide leader. He carries his pistols in a lawyers portfolio, 4
    - Verso: American from Galveston who was in Germany when war broke out. He became a U-boat sailor and is now a Sparticide leader. He carries his pistols in a lawyers portfolio, 4-verso
    - Note: L.T. and an Italian General standing before the famous wooden idol of Von Hindenburg, in Berlin. This mammoth statue of the Field Marshal was hurled down a few days later during the German revolution. At this particular time L.T. was preparing a historical record of the Spartacus revolt in Germany, 5
    - L.T. and an Italian General standing before the famous wooden idol of Von Hindenburg, in Berlin. This mammoth statue of the Field Marshal was hurled down a few days later during the German revolution. At this particular time L.T. was preparing a historical record of the Spartacus revolt in Germany, 6
    - Note: L.T. (on the right), in front of famous giant wooden image of Hindenburg. Picture taken during the German Revolution, just before the celebrated statue was demolished; Verso: The Hindenburg Idol, 7
    - L.T. (on the right), in front of famous giant wooden image of Hindenburg. Picture taken during the German Revolution, just before the celebrated statue was demolished; Verso: The Hindenburg Idol (2 copies), 8
    - Verso: The Hindenberg Idol, 8-verso
  - Subject files: Greece, circa 1917 - 1918; 3 (Box 1513)
    - L.T. on the Acropolis at Athens, 1
    - Verso: L.T. on the Acropolis at Athens, 1-verso
    - Salonika, important wartime seaport and base of the Allied armies, on the Macedonian front, only a few miles from where the armies of Greece, Serbia, France, and Great Britain faced the Bulgarian army and its reenforcements [sic] from Austria and Germany, 2
    - Note: Salonika, important wartime seaport and base of the Allied armies, on the Macedonian front, only a few miles from where the armies of Greece, Serbia, France, and Great Britain faced the Bulgarian army and its reenforcements [sic] from Austria and Germany, 3
  - Subject files: Illustrations for With Lawrence in Arabia by Lowell Thomas, 1918; 4 (Box 1513)
    - A Bedouin raider from Transjordania; Copyright: Lowell Thomas, 1
    - Verso: A Bedouin raider from Transjordania; Copyright: Lowell Thomas, 1-verso
    - A typical Arab warrior - one of Lawrence's famous bodyguard, 2
    - Verso: A typical Arab warrior - one of Lawrence's famous bodyguard, 2-verso
    - [A Bedouin raider from Transjordania], 3
    - Field-Marshal Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 4
    - Verso: Field-Marshal Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 4-verso
    - Field-Marshal Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad, 5
    - Verso: Field-Marshal Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad, 5-verso
    - [Field-Marshal Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas in Arabia], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas in Arabia], 8
    - [Three men looking at papers in Arabia (?)], 9
    - [Militarty (?) vehicles in Arabia (?)], 10
    - [Old building set in rock in Arabia (?)], 11
    - When he was still in his twenties Ned Lawrence had created two kings and one sultan. Since the war he has vanished in order to avoid curiosity of the public. Chap. 25 -38, 12
    - Verso: When he was still in his twenties Ned Lawrence had created two kings and one sultan. Since the war he has vanished in order to avoid curiosity of the public. Chap. 25 -38, 12-verso
    - [Three men looking at papers in Arabia], 13
    - Col. Lawrence conferring with Commander D. G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau of Cairo, 14
    - Verso: Col. Lawrence conferring with Commander D. G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau of Cairo, 14-verso
    - Col. Lawrence conferring with Commander D. G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau of Cairo (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 15
    - Verso: Col. Lawrence conferring with Commander D. G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau of Cairo (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 15-verso
    - [Colonel Lawrence conferring with Commander D.G. Hogarth (?)], 16
    - [Herd of camels in Arabia], 17
    - WITH LAWRENCE IN ARABIA. In late 1917, Lowell Thomas, American war correspondent, went to the Middle East to cover the Arab Revolt against the Turks, led by a young Englishman, Col. T.E. Lawrence, the most romantic and most contradictory figure of his era. Now that Sam Spiegel and David Lean are bringing to the screen the story of "Lawrence of Arabia", with Peter O'Toole in the title role, surrounded by an all-star cast, the pictures taken by Lowell Thomas and his photographer, Harry Chase, have special significance. Thomas's own captions are used here. LTh-17 Colonel Lawrence conferring with Commander D.G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau of Cairo, 18
    - Note: "WITH LAWRENCE IN ARABIA". In late 1917, Lowell Thomas, American war correspondent, went to the Middle East to cover the Arab Revolt against the Turks, led by a young Englishman, Col. T.E. Lawrence, the most romantic and most contradictory figure of his era. Now that Sam Spiegel and David Lean are bringing to the screen the story of "Lawrence of Arabia", with Peter O'Toole in the title role, surrounded by an all-star cast, the pictures taken by Lowell Thomas and his photographer, Harry Chase, have special significance. Thomas's own captions are used here. LTh-17 Colonel Lawrence conferring with Commander D.G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau of Cairo, 19
    - Colonel Lawrence and Commander D. G. Hogarth, 20
    - Verso: Colonel Lawrence and Commander D. G. Hogarth, 20-verso
    - Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab "Regulars." (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 21
    - Verso: 1-64; Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab "Regulars." (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 21-verso
    - Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab "Regulars", 22
    - Verso: 1-64; Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab "Regulars", 22-verso
    - Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab "Regulars", 23
    - Note: Lowell Thomas's caravan approaching the "enchanted" red mountains of Edom in Arabia where they visited the long lost city of Petra carved out of solid rocks., 24
    - Caravan approaching the "Lost City" (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas) Note: Lowell Thomas's caravan approaching red mountains of Edom in Arabia where they visited the long lost city of Petra carved out of solid rocks, 25
    - Verso: Caravan approaching the "Lost City" (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas) Note: Lowell Thomas's caravan approaching red mountains of Edom in Arabia where they visited the long lost city of Petra carved out of solid rocks, 25-verso
    - [Caravan approaching the "Lost City"], 26
    - [Caravan approaching the "Lost City"], 27
    - [Caravan approaching the "Lost City"], 28
    - [Caravan approaching the "Lost City"], 29
    - [The "Lost City" (?) in Arabia], 30
    - [The "Lost City" (?), Arabia], 31
    - [Bedouin "Irregulars" ready for a raid against the Turks], 32
    - [Bedouin "Irregulars" ready for a raid against the Turks], 33
    - Bedouin "Irregulars" ready for a raid against the Turks (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 34
    - Verso: Bedouin "Irregulars" ready for a raid against the Turks (only to be used by permission of Lowell Thomas), 34-verso
    - [Men on horses, Arabia], 35
    - [Arabian city (?)], 36
    - Arab peasant woman of Palestine; Copyright-Lowell Thomas, 37
    - Verso: Arab peasant woman of Palestine; Copyright-Lowell Thomas, 37-verso
    - WITH LAWRENCE IN ARABIA. In late 1917, Lowell Thomas, American war correspondent, went to the Middle East to cover the Arab Revolt against the Turks, led by a young Englishman, Col. T.E. Lawrence, the most romantic and most contradictory figure of his era. Now that Sam Spiegel and David Lean are bringing to the screen the story of "Lawrence of Arabia", with Peter O'Toole in the title role, surrounded by an all-star cast, the pictures taken by Lowell Thomas and his photographer, Harry Chase, have special significance. Thomas's own captions are used here; LTh-21 Feisal and Lawrence (far right, seated) conferring with Bedouin sheikhs, 38
    - Note: "WITH LAWRENCE IN ARABIA". In late 1917, Lowell Thomas, American war correspondent, went to the Middle East to cover the Arab Revolt against the Turks, led by a young Englishman, Col. T.E. Lawrence, the most romantic and most contradictory figure of his era. Now that Sam Spiegel and David Lean are bringing to the screen the story of "Lawrence of Arabia", with Peter O'Toole in the title role, surrounded by an all-star cast, the pictures taken by Lowell Thomas and his photographer, Harry Chase, have special significance. Thomas's own captions are used here; LTh-21 Feisal and Lawrence (far right, seated) conferring with Bedouin sheikhs, 39
    - Doubleday & Company, 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017; Title: With Lawrence in Arabia, 40
    - Verso: Doubleday & Company, 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017; Title: With Lawrence in Arabia, 40-verso
    - Pharaoh's Treasury or The "Temple of Isis"; Doubleday & Company, 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017; Title: With Lawrence in Arabia, 41
    - Verso: "Pharaoh's Treasury" or The "Temple of Isis"; Doubleday & Company, 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017; Title: With Lawrence in Arabia, 41-verso
    - Armored cars in Holy Arabia; Doubleday & Company, 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017; Title: With Lawrence in Arabia, 42
    - Verso: Armored cars in Holy Arabia; Doubleday & Company, 277 Park Avenue, New York, N.Y. 10017; Title: With Lawrence in Arabia, 42
    - [Men with guns in Arabia], 43
  - Subject files: Italy, circa 1917 - 1918; 5 (Box 1513)
    - L.T., third from the left, standing with a group of Italian officers, at an altitude of thirteen thousand feet, in mid-winter on an Alpine peak, during the World War, when the Austrians and Italians were fighting in the High Alps, 1
    - Verso: L.T., third from the left, standing with a group of Italian officers, at an altitude of thirteen thousand feet, in mid-winter on an Alpine peak, during the World War, when the Austrians and Italians were fighting in the High Alps, 1-verso
    - L.T. third from the left, in the Italian Alps; Verso: Lowell Thomas and staff on top of high Alpin peak; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 2
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and staff on top of high Alpin peak, 2-verso
    - Note: L.T. third from the left, in the Italian Alps; Verso: Lowell Thomas and staff on top of high Alpin peak; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 3
    - Lowell Thomas, third from left, in the Italian Alps, 4
    - Note: Lowell Thomas, third from left, in the Italian Alps, 5
    - [Lowell Thomas, thirs from left, in the Italian Alps], 6
    - L.T. with his back to the camera, and His Royal Highness the Prince of Wales, in front of the Cathedral of St. Mark's in Venice, 7
    - Note: L.T. with his back to the camera, and His Royal Highness the Prince of Wales, in front of the Cathedral of St. Mark's in Venice, 8
    - L.T. with pointed campaign hat, in rear seat, accompanied by his assistants en route to the Italian front; In middle Gen. Webb Hayes, son of U.S. Pres. Rutherford B. Hayes; on right in rear seat Col. Piero Tozzi, Italian staff officer, 9
    - Note: L.T. with pointed campaign hat, in rear seat, accompanied by his assistants en route to the Italian front; In middle Gen. Webb Hayes, son of U.S. Pres. Rutherford B. Hayes; on right in rear seat Col. Piero Tozzi, Italian staff officer, 10
    - L.T., and his associate, Col. Webb Hayes, son of Ex-President of the U.S.A., Rutherford B. Hayes, with the Italian army, 11
    - Verso: L.T., and his associate, Col. Webb Hayes, son of Ex-President of the U.S.A., Rutherford B. Hayes, with the Italian army, 11-verso
    - Lowell Thomas, American world traveler, Col. Webb C. Hayes, son of ex President Hayes, Capt. Piero Tozzi of the Italian army on the Italian Front; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 12
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas, American world traveler, Col. Webb C. Hayes, son of ex President Hayes, Capt. Piero Tozzi of the Italian army on the Italian Front; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 12-verso
    - L.T. and party on photographic expedition, bound for the Italian front, 13
    - Verso: L.T. and party on photographic expedition, bound for the Italian front, 13-verso
    - [L.T. and party on photpgraphic expedition, bound for the Italian front], 14
    - [L.T. and party on photographic expedition, bound for the Italian front], 15
    - [L.T. and party on photographic expedition, bound for the Italian front], 16
    - Sand bagged Golden Stairs in Doges Palace, Venice, Dome of St. Mark's in back-ground; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 17
    - Verso: Sand bagged Golden Stairs in Doges Palace, Venice, Dome of St. Mark's in back-ground; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 17-verso
    - An officer of the Italian Alpini military organization; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 18
    - Verso: An officer of the Italian Alpini military organization; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 18-verso
    - Imitation of an Esquimeaux igloo on Italian front amid the glacier fields of the highest Alps., 19
    - Verso: Imitation of an Esquimeaux igloo on Italian front amid the glacier fields of the highest Alps., 19-verso
    - Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 20
    - Verso: Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 20-verso
    - Piero Tozzi, 21
    - Verso: Piero Tozzi, 21-verso
    - Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 22
    - Verso: Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 22-verso
    - St. Mark's, closeup; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 23
    - Verso: St. Mark's, closeup; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 23-verso
    - The Capanile in Verona; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 24
    - Verso: The Capanile in Verona; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 24-verso
    - Italian Alps; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 25
    - Verso: Italian Alps; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 25-verso
    - Italian Alps; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 26
    - Verso: Italian Alps; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 26-verso
    - I spent one Christmas with the famous Italian Alpine troops, on skis at an altitude of 13,000 feet; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 27
    - Verso: I spent one Christmas with the famous Italian Alpine troops, on skis at an altitude of 13,000 feet; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 27-verso
    - Alpini; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 28
    - Verso: Alpini; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 28-verso
    - Alpini; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 29
    - Verso: Alpini; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 29-verso
    - Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 30
    - Verso: Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 30-verso
    - Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 31
    - Verso: Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 31-verso
  - Subject files: Italy, circa 1917 - 1918; 6 (Box 1513)
    - Venice 1917; L.T., 1
    - Verso: Venice 1917; L.T., 1-verso
    - Snapshot of L.T. taken standing on one of the lofty peaks of the Italian Alps, in mid-winter. The temperature is below zero most of the time. This was when he was with an Italian regiment on skis. The war in the High Alps was being fought from mountain peak to mountain peak, 2
    - Snapshot of L.T. taken standing on one of the lofty peaks of the Italian Alps, in mid-winter. The temperature is below zero most of the time. This was when he was with an Italian regiment on skis. The war in the High Alps was being fought from mountain peak to mountain peak, 3
    - Note: Snapshot of L.T. taken standing on one of the lofty peaks of the Italian Alps, in mid-winter. The temperature is below zero most of the time. This was when he was with an Italian regiment on skis. The war in the High Alps was being fought from mountain peak to mountain peak, 4
    - [L.T. standing on one of the lofty peaks of the Italian Alps, in mid-winter.], 5
    - L.T. and his party making films with the Italian army in the High Alps, 6
    - Note: L.T. and his party making films with the Italian army in the High Alps, 7
    - [L.T. and his party making films with the Italian army in the High Alps], 8
    - [L.T. and his party making films with the Italian army in the High Alps], 9
    - An Alpine scout pointing out the Austrian positions from the frozen summit of one of the lofty peaks in the Italian Alps; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 10
    - Note: An Alpine scout pointing out the Austrian positions from the frozen summit of one of the lofty peaks in the Italian Alps; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 11
    - General Peppino Garibaldi, grandson of great Liberator, 12
    - General Peppino Garibaldi, grandson of great Liberator. Lowell Thomas on the right; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 13
    - Verso: General Peppino Garibaldi, grandson of great Liberator. Lowell Thomas on the right; Comando Supremo Censura Fotografica, 13-verso
    - General Peppino Garibaldi, grandson of great Liberator, 14
    - [Italian man in uniform, Italy], 15
  - Subject files: Italy, circa 1917 - 1918; 7 (Box 1513)
    - L.T. on the left, in company with an Italian soldier, inspecting an observation post in No Man's Land, upon the Asiago Plateau, 1
    - Note: L.T. on the left, in company with an Italian soldier, inspecting an observation post in No Man's Land, upon the Asiago Plateau, 2
    - Col Webb C Hayes son Pres Hayes Grand Canal Venice; L.T. and Piero Tozzi, 3
    - Verso: Col Webb C Hayes son Pres Hayes Grand Canal Venice; L.T. and Piero Tozzi, 3-verso
    - [Colonel Webb C. Hayes son President Hays Grand Canal Venice; L.T. and Piero Tozzi], 4
    - Madame Tetrazzini and P. Tozzi, 5
    - Verso: Madame Tetrazzini and P. Tozzi, 5-verso
    - Major Tozzi, who was attached to Lowell Thomas, in Italy, during the war; Madame Tetrazzini and L.T.'s father, Captain (now Colonel) H. G. Thomas, in Italy during the World War, 6
    - Note: Major Tozzi, who was attached to Lowell Thomas, in Italy, during the war; Madame Tetrazzini and L.T.'s father, Captain (now Colonel) H. G. Thomas, in Italy during the World War, 7
    - [Madame Tetrazzini and Piero Tozzi], 8
    - [Madame Tetrazzini and Piero Tozzi], 9
    - Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G.; Ad Astra-Aero; Aviation Suisse S.A.; Zurich; Fliegeranfnahme = Photo prise d'avion. Swiss, 10
    - Verso: Schweiz. Luftverkehrs-A.-G.; Ad Astra-Aero; Aviation Suisse S.A.; Zurich; Fliegeranfnahme = Photo prise d'avion. Swiss, 10-verso
    - Dugouts along Piave front in Italy, 11
    - Verso: Dugouts along Piave front in Italy, 11-verso
    - L.T. talking to an Italian woman as she sits amid the ruins of her home, just back of the front line, 12
    - Note: L.T. talking to an Italian woman as she sits amid the ruins of her home, just back of the front line, 13
    - L.T. looking down on the fires of Vulcan - a birds eye view of the crater of Vesuvius, 14
    - Verso: L.T. looking down on the fires of Vulcan - a birds eye view of the crater of Vesuvius, 14-verso
    - Home Sweet Home - after a few days' shelling. This was typical of the towns and cities along the Italian front, all the way from the Adriatic to the Alps. WWII, 15
    - Note: Home Sweet Home - after a few days' shelling. This was typical of the towns and cities along the Italian front, all the way from the Adriatic to the Alps. WWII, 16
    - [Elderly woman standing in rubble, Italy], 17
  - Subject files: Malta, circa 1917 - 1919; 8 (Box 1513)
    - Admiral Lord Calthorpe, 2nd British Sea Lord, on the roof of his headquarters on the Island of Malta. L.T.'s ship enroute to Palestine was chased into Malta by U-boats. Lord Calthorpe is explaining his defenses to L.T. The officer on the right is Lt. Com. Chas. Dickens, grandson of the novelist, 1
    - Verso: Admiral Lord Calthorpe, 2nd British Sea Lord, on the roof of his headquarters on the Island of Malta. L.T.'s ship enroute to Palestine was chased into Malta by U-boats. Lord Calthorpe is explaining his defenses to L.T. The officer on the right is Lt. Com. Chas. Dickens, grandson of the novelist, 1-verso
    - L.T. having his credentials inspected while attempting to film some of the fortifications of the islands of the Mediterranean, 2
    - Note: L.T. having his credentials inspected while attempting to film some of the fortifications of the islands of the Mediterranean, 3
    - [L.T. having his credentials inspected while attempting to film some of the fortification of the islands of the Mediterranean], 4
    - Vallette cap[ital of] Malta [?] pix, 5
    - Verso: Vallette cap[ital of] Malta [?] pix, 5-verso
    - L.T. on the right, being welcomed at the city of Vallette, capital of the island of Malta. On the left is the American consul, and with him two representatives of the British Admiral in command of the Mediterranean fleet, 6
    - Note: L.T. on the right, being welcomed at the city of Vallette, capital of the island of Malta. On the left is the American consul, and with him two representatives of the British Admiral in command of the Mediterranean fleet, 7
    - Admiral Ballard, head of British Naval base on Island of Malta and Lowell Thomas, 8
    - Verso: Admiral Ballard, head of British Naval base on Island of Malta and Lowell Thomas, 8-verso
    - [L.T. on the right, being welcomed at the city of Vallette, capital of the island of Malta.], 9
    - [Admiral Ballard, head of British Naval base on Island of Malta and Lowell Thomas], 10
    - Women of Malta who dress in black because they are mourning for the sins of their grandmothers, 11
    - Verso: Women of Malta who dress in black because they are mourning for the sins of their grandmothers, 11-verso
    - [Women of Malta who dress in black because they are mourning for the sins of their grandmothers], 12
    - [Women of Malta who dress in black because they are mourning for the sins of their grandmothers], 13
    - [Looking out over Malta], 14
    - [Looking out over Malta], 15
  - Subject files: Photographs found among Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas's papers, circa 1917 - 1918; 9 (Box 1513)
    - Trying to keep cool in Rome, 1
    - Verso: Trying to keep cool in Rome, 1-verso
    - Lowell and Frances Thomas, 2
    - Verso: Lowell and Frances Thomas, 2-verso
    - [Lowell and Fances Thomas], 3
    - St. Mark's Venice, 4
    - Verso: St. Mark's Venice, 4-verso
    - In the Forum at Rome. Mrs. Marcus Brutus and Mr. Julius Caesar, 5
    - Verso: In the Forum at Rome. Mrs. Marcus Brutus and Mr. Julius Caesar, 5-verso
    - They saw our machine here and sent some fire over but it didn't come very close, 6